

# TOBY TOMKINSON

### **Developer & Computer Science Graduate**

- @ tobytomkinson@hotmail.co.nz
- **J** 027-239-5676
- Auckland, New Zealand

- in toby-j-tomkinson
- (7) ttom795
- ttom795.github.io

# TECH SKILLS

### **Programming Languages:**

Python C# C++ JavaScript

SQL LaTeX

#### Web Development:

MongoDB Express.js React

Node.js TypeScript HTML

CSS Vite

#### Software:

Microsoft Office Git & GitHub

Google Workspace Nagios

Unity Engine Mono .NET

Unreal Engine 4 & 5

#### **Operating Systems:**

Windows OSX/MacOS

Debian Ubuntu ArchLinux

#### **Development Methods:**

Agile Scrum Kanban

Waterfall Pair Programming

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Red Cross Comprehensive First Aid

ICDL Certified

# **SOFT SKILLS**

Attention to Detail | Quick Learner

Adaptability Multitasking Abilities

Effective Communication

Teamwork and Collaboration

Time Management | Creativity

# **LANGUAGES**

English: Native

German: Conversational Vietnamese: Beginner Japanese: Beginner

# **ABOUT ME**

I am a hardworking and reliable individual with a strong computer and technology-oriented background. I thrive in environments where I am exposed to a variety of experiences and challenges and I have a strong desire to constantly improve myself.

With 4 years of experience with Python, C# and C++, I have a solid foundation as a developer. From 2020, the university introduced me to JavaScript, SQL, and web development tools including MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js, and TypeScript.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### Administrative Receptionist | University of Auckland

Nov 2022 - Current

- Auckland, New Zealand
- Managed front-desk and general accommodation operations from resident queries to introduction of new processes and workflow streamlining.
- I have implemented automated systems to streamline the recording of resident lockouts and issuance of temporary access cards, improving efficiency.

#### Graduate Teaching Assistant | University of Auckland

- Feb 2022 July 2023
- Auckland, New Zealand
- Provided tutoring, graded assignments/tests and provided constructive feedback through evaulation for COMPSCI 215 and COMPSCI 315.
- I created a useful program bridging Dividni and Canvas to automate formatting and delivery of of marks.

### Research Assistant | University of Auckland

- Nov 2021 Feb 2022
- Auckland, New Zealand
- · Worked with Dr. Ulrich Speidel.
- I developed software and a novel routing algorithm for use with Low Earth Orbit satellites (available here) using the Unity Real-Time Development Platform.

#### Research Assistant | University of Auckland

**Jun 2021 – Oct 2021** 

- Auckland, New Zealand
- · Worked with Dr. Alex Shaw.
- I developed a procedural construction site for Virtual Reality-based risk assessment training for City Rail Link using the Unity Real-Time Development Platform.

#### C++ Developer | Beyond Studios

Nov 2019 - Current

- Remote, United States
- Responsible for gameplay design, developing game systems using C++, designing gameplay mechanics and optimising code.

# REFERENCES

Available on request

# MOST PROUD OF



#### **Academic Results**

I've received no marks below an A grade for the last 3 years of my study with a final GPA of 8.122/9 or 3.8/4.0



### **Dissertation Completion**

I developed a novel satellite routing algorithm for Low Earth Orbit satellite networks as the focus of my dissertation. This not only received high praise from my academic mentors but also an A+ grade from the University of Auckland.



# Volunteer Staff - Burnett Foundation Aotearoa

I take great pride in my volunteer work at the Burnett Foundation Aotearoa, where I help package condoms for distribution, contributing to their mission of promoting safe practices and HIV prevention.

# **HOBBIES**



#### Gaming

Avid fan of RPG games. Currently working my way through *Baldur's Gate 3*.



#### **Exercise**

I'm a regular gym-goer and a Muay Thai amateur. I'm a firm believer of the adage "a healthy body is a healthy mind".



### Reading

I love adventure novels and comedy - Terry Pratchett, Douglas Adams, and Bill Bryson for example.

### Sales Assistant | Jaycar New Lynn

- Nov 2020 Mar 2022
- Auckland, New Zealand
- Managed clients' needs and budgets to an exceptional level and developed strong company relationships through repeat customers.

### Software Developer | Gladstone Games

Feb 2017 - Current

- Remote, United States
- Responsible for ensuring a good user experience and gameplay balance, optimising code, implementing asynchronous scene/object/player instantiation and loading, and designing level layouts.
- I have multifaceted role that involves both game design concepts and C# development, contributing to both the creative and technical aspects of the team.

## **EDUCATION**

### Bachelor of Science | University of Auckland

**=** Feb 2019 – Jun 2022

Auckland, New Zealand

Bachelor of Science (BSc) majoring in Computer Science.

### Bachelor of Science (Honours) | University of Auckland

**ä** Jul 2022 – Jun 2023

Auckland, New Zealand

Bachelor of Science Honours (BSc Hons) majoring in Computer Science.

My dissertation explored a novel pathfinding algorithm for Low Earth Orbit satellite networks - an improved version of my project done as a research assistant in 2022. The honours degree included coursework, a dissertation as well as the simulation software developed in Unity Engine using C#.

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

## Low Earth Orbit Satellite Simulator | # | Unity Engine & C#

Simulates and visualises approximate great circle routing in Low Earth Orbit satellite networks. This project was iterated on for my dissertation.

# Hero Academia: Beyond | # | Unreal Engine & C++

As a game designer and programmer for "Hero Academia: Beyond," I designed gameplay mechanics, environments, and ported the game from desktop to mobile with full gameplay, rendering and post-processing functionality.

\_\_\_\_\_

# Orangutan Monitor | • | C++ & OpenGL

A standalone software application designed to monitor page-file size efficiently, useful when paired with memory-intensive programs like Yuzu. This tool comes as a single .exe file without the need for additional dependencies or DLLs.

\_\_\_\_\_

# Chippure | # | Python

Chippure is a Python-based Chip-8 emulator developed using Python's default libraries. It emulates the Chip-8 system and allows users to play Chip-8 games on modern hardware, and demonstrates the effectiveness of Python's default libraries in building emulation software.

### Various Games | Unreal Engine & C++

- \$\Bigset\$ | Showcase Shonen Jump Game
- \$\rightarrow\$ | Showcase Shield Hero Fangame
- # | Showcase Mob Psycho Sentiment